# Adrian Urdar

Braşov, Romania



adrian.urdar@gmail.com



+40732513832



linkedin.com/in/adrianurdar

# **Summary**

My job is to create processes, solve problems, and remove bottlenecks.

I'm a Product Manager with 3+ years of experience in building SaaS and Digital E-commerce products, with a background of 8+ years in sales that enabled me to balance and align software development with business strategy and goals.

#### Key competences:

- Received a Project Management Certificate from the Romanian Ministry of Labor.

#### Key achievements:

- Increased operational efficiency by 20% by adjusting the Agile and Scrum methodologies to meet the business needs;
- Worked with teams and clients on projects delivered on Vue.js, PHP (Laravel 8), Python, HTML5 and CSS, and JavaScript by implementing Agile and Scrum Methodologies;

I love to consult, contribute and add value to an organization.

# **Experience**

# ( IT Project Manager

Carrefour România

Mar 2021 - Present (5 months +)

- Helped the IT Digital Department implement unified documentation across all 6 IT components that covered Digital Platforms
- Organized all the documentation for the 6 Bringo applications (web, iOS, Android, Sales, Accounting, and Delivery)
- Prioritized and managed 69 projects for the 2021 Roadmap using the RICE prioritization framework and JIRA
- Translating business requirements into Product Requirements for all projects on the roadmap
- Acting as the Product Manager for the Bringo ecosystem
- Providing guidance and direction to business stakeholders & technical providers
- Ensuring the high-level software documentation is clearly understood and documented
- Cross-working with multiple technology vendors (technical architects, developers, technical analyst) and internal stakeholders (Business analysts, Product owners)

# **Information Technology Business Consultant**

Urdar Adrian Razvan PFA

Mar 2019 - Present (2 years 5 months +)

- Reducing costs for 10 small and medium business clients by 10% over the year by automating their workflow with chatbots
- Growing revenue for 3 SMBs (a development start-up and 2 brick and mortar shops) by creating 100% of their Standard Operating Procedures
- Helping a small company in the education industry reach 10,000+ potential clients by setting up its email autoresponder

#### Product Owner for FutureMindsFund

ScholarshipOwl

Apr 2020 - Mar 2021 (1 year)

- Managing a 4-member technical team to support a marketing project resulting in 10,000+ scholarship applications submitted, \$35,000 donations received in 4 months, and 58,000 monthly users
- Successfully launched a 501(c)(3) project tied to the EdTech industry on the US market



# Product Manager for ScholarshipApp

ScholarshipOwl

Jan 2019 - Mar 2021 (2 years 3 months)

- Leading a 4-member Agile product team to develop and implement a SaaS service resulting in 171 scholarships (\$271,024) offered and 172 clients onboarded (with no ad budget) in the first 12 months
- Written and prioritized over 1,000 User Stories with the technical team aligning with business goals



# **Customer Success Manager**

ScholarshipOwl

Sep 2017 - Apr 2020 (2 years 8 months)

- Led the support team for servicing over 5.3 million users by creating and automating procedures for the workflow
- Improved customer satisfaction level to 92%+ (previously 80%) by implementing a help-desk system



# **Business Development Manager**

Marketing Research Solutions

Aug 2014 - Aug 2017 (3 years 1 month)

- Contributed to a 21% increase in productivity of the sales team by achieving 166% of the target number of contacts (250 contacts per day)



# Business Development Representative

Marketing Research Solutions

Sep 2011 - Aug 2014 (3 years)

### Education



# IIII Universitatea Transilvania din Brasov

Bachelor of Business Administration (B.B.A.), Business, Management, Marketing, and Related Support Services

2008 - 2011

Colegiul National de Informatica "Grigore Moisil" din Brasov
Computer driving license and programming, Computer Science
2004 - 2008

# **Licenses & Certifications**

- Corporate Trainer Romanian Ministry of Labor and Social Justice
- ManyChat Agency Partner ManyChat
- Project Management Professional (PMP) Romanian Ministry of Labor and Social Justice
- CS50x Introduction to Computer Science CS50
- CS50b Computer Science for Business Professionals CS50
- in Become a Project Manager LinkedIn

# **Skills**

Strategic Vision • Agile Methodologies • Project Management • Market Research • Sales & Marketing • Business Strategy • Operations Management • Technical Understanding • User Stories • User Experience (UX)

# **Honors & Awards**

ScholarshipOwl's Employee Of The Year (2020) - ScholarshipOwl Jan 2021